Climbing the tree with the best view in this area
いい
って
I dream of that girl laughing — laughing innocently
If you look closely at the place past where fish swam in the sky
っと
You'll see days giving their color to every corner of the city
っこ
Even if you say good-bye with just a pinky promise,
I'll just dwell in this tree and wait until the day it's fulfilled
って
We repeat this again and again — every time we cry
We stop and start again, as if to confirm every step
って
よう
に
Listen — you can hear an echo
Hotaru Had Fun
Episode 13
S... Snow!
It's snow!
There's snow everywhere, Pechi!
Do you like snow too, Pechi?
Ah, Pechi! There's ice on the river here!
See... You've never seen a piece of ice this big, have you?
It's beautiful, isn't it?
Ah, that's right!
Pechi, let's build a snowman.
A really big one!
I'm done!
Pechi, how is it? It's a splendid snowman, right?
Should I make something else...?
Ah, right!
If I step on this snow hill...
...I can make a slide!
Pechi, let's slide together.
Are you ready?
Ready... go!
I...It's so much fun!
Pechi, do you want to slide again?
Pechi?
What are you digging?
I guess you like snow too, Pechi.
Then, I'll make something good for you, Pechi!
It's done!
Pechi's mini-igloo!
Yes! It's not bad!
Pechi, it's a snow house.
I guess we've played too much in the snow.
Let's go home and take a warm bath.
If there's still snow tomorrow, let's come play again!
Ah... Snowy days are so much fun!
Mother! I'm going to play at Hotaru's house!
Okay! Come back by dinnertime!
Alright!
With this snow, it's going to be hard to get to
Hotaru's house... Maybe I should take a shortcut.
It's pretty packed with snow!
Hotaru and I can play a lot together with all this snow!
What is this?
That's dangerous!
A snowman?
Why is there a slide here?
And it seems to lead to a hole-like thing...
Stop... Stop!
Pechi, was your bath warm?
Hm? I wonder who it is.
Yes!
Hotaru!
Komari-senpai! Welco—
Hotaru! It's dangerous to play on a snowy day,
so let's stay inside the house!
What happened Komari-senpai!?
Senpai, is the kuzuyu warm?
Yeah, it is.
I'm sorry, Hotaru-chan.
I'll be back before it gets dark.
Okay. Tell Aunt that I send my regards.
Let's bake cookies some other time.
Okay!
I'll leave some allowance money right here.
Then, I'll be going!
Be careful!
Come to think of it, it might be my
first time going to the candy shop alone.
Hello!
Welcome. Oh, it's Hotaru.
Are you alone today?
Yes.
You coming in?
Y-Yes.
What should I do? What should I say?
Um...
Yeah.
Do you have any cookies?
Ah... Sorry. We don't have any right now.
Is that right?
Do you have any vanilla essence?
We don't have that here.
We can order some if you want, though.
Ah, no... Um... How about brown sugar?
Sorry. We're out of it.
Um... How about almond powder?
We have this if you want.
Appetizer
Almond
Grown in
California
Crunchy
taste
Best
Flavored.
Uh... It's okay...
What a nice day.
You're right.
What should I do? I can't keep the conversation going...
What did Ren-chan always talk about?
Hotaru-chan, do you like cookies?
Ah, yes. Actually, I had planned
to bake cookies with my mom today,
but because of a sudden errand, we can't anymore...
Ah... So that's why you're in the mood for cookies.
Yes.
Is that right? Do you want to bake some
with me? If that's okay with you...
Eh?
If it's the ingredients, our kitchen has it.
I was just planning to take a break anyway.
But... are you sure?
I can't promise anything about the taste, though.
And I can leave the shop to this guy for a bit.
Yes! Yes please!
First, get the ingredients ready.
What is this?
Those are dried and salted cherry blossoms.
This is my first time seeing some! They're very cute!
They smell good, too.
They're used to make cherry blossom tea
or they're put on top of steamed buns.
However, they're good on top of cookies too!
Okay, first...
They look so cute!
Like this...
Yes!
After you put on the flowers like this,
put it in the oven, and it's done!
If I had an older sister, I wonder if it would be like this.
Do you want to try, Hotaru-chan?
Yes!
Oh, I'm sorry. I'll be right back, so keep at it.
Oh, okay!
Oh, welcome!
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Let's put the cookies in the oven!
Yes!
It looks like it went well.
Yes. It smells nice and yummy!
Let's make some tea and take them downstairs.
Yes!
Thank you so much for today.
It was so much fun! I even got some presents...
I'm glad it turned out well.
I'll teach you how to bake different
types of cookies some other time.
Okay!
Ah... I'm so tired!
Natsumi, you've barely done any of your homework yet!
The last day of summer vacation
is going to be a pain for you again!
This is wrong too.
You write this part like this.
Koma-chan's wrong too. It's like this.
That's amazing, Ren-chan!
I'm surprised that you know that!
Uh... Oh that's right, that's right.
Koma-chan, this one is wrong, too.
Eh? Ah, this one is wrong too.
In each
(  ),
fill in
the kanji
that
completes
the
saying.
Keep
each
meeting
important.
Our
heart
and
body
are
one.
word
body
Koma-chan, I'm better than you at writing kanji.
I'm going to take a break...
The rest of you, work hard...
Uh oh, she's sulking now.
W... What should we do?
Let's play Koma-chan's favorite games
and invite her to play with us!
I guess we have no choice.
Nee-chan!
Did she go to bed to spite us?
She's fast at falling asleep.
It also seems wrong to wake her up,
so I suppose we can just leave her like this.
Kanji...
First grade...
She's still moping over that...
Isn't it better to wake her up?
I just had an amazing idea!
What is it?
It seems like Koma-chan is having a bad dream.
We should help her out so she can have good dreams!
What do you mean?
We have to change her dreams from the outside.
When Nee Nee doesn't wake up, I change her dream to a nightmare and make her wake up.
It should work on Koma-chan too!
Ren-chan, you do such things?
But that seems fun.
First, we should put something that smells good nearby, and change her dream to a food fest!
You can do that?!
I hope this turns out okay...
Dried sardine.
Chocolate.
I brought curry roux but...
Well then! Let's start out with Hotarun's!
Okay...
Senpai laughed! Does that mean she got
to eat curry in her sleep?
Hotarun, shh!
See, you were being so loud that Nee-chan got scared!
Ah, s-sorry!
To fix Koma-chan's mood, I'll put down the chocolate!
I'll put down the dried sardines.
It tastes like iron...
She doesn't look like she's enjoying it...
Maybe putting them all together was a mistake.
Let's take back the dried sardine and the chocolate.
She's still not smiling like before...
We need a Plan B.
Something different?
First, we need to change the setting,
so Koma-chan feels like she is outside.
How?
I need something that can replace the sun...
Does a light work?
I want you to point that on Koma-chan!
But be careful, don't shine it directly on her face!
Okay...
It kinda of looks like Komari-senpai is in pain...
Is it too bright?
But it's too hot, so I can't cover it with my hand...
Do you want to try hiding it with that mirror?
Yes please!
This stuffed animal is in the way, so let's move it.
Um... It looks like Senpai started crying
when you took her stuffed animal...
Eh? No way, she is in middle school!
Uh... I guess so...
Ren-chon, what are you planning to do next?
We'll use this mat.
We'll send her wind like this
and make her dream about flying!
A dream about flying sounds like fun!
Then, I'll send some air to Koma-chan!
Grandmas covered in zippers are chasing me...
Uh oh! It turned into a horror!
I never thought some light and wind would lead to this....
I can't leave Natsumi behind...
Uh oh! I'm in her dream!
And I'm going to be killed by the zipper grandmas!
Isn't it better to just wake her up...?
Not yet...
I'm going to bend this mat
and make it sound like she's flying.
Is that how flying sounds like!?
I don't know!
But it's worth a try!
Oh yeah... I can escape by flying...
Why can't I move unless I dog paddle...?
Oh no! Even if she's flying, dog paddling won't work!
Ren-chon!
I know! I'm putting all of my power into this!
She laughed! Senpai laughed!
Yay!
We won!
Mmm... What?
Eh...!?
Hey, do you all want to eat some jelly?
It's really starting to feel like autumn now.
It sure is.
I wonder if we can go leaf peeping soon.
Autumn leaves are great.
But didn't we come here today
to go on an adventure to gather tree nuts?
If you're all bubbly like that, what are you going to do when an enemy shows up?
Well, we didn't come here to go an adventure.
Also, what do you mean by enemy?
There's no way that there's any enemies here.
Ouch!
What? Did I just get hit by someone?
An acorn came falling down.
Ah, look Senpai!
There's something on top of the tree.
Is that a squirrel?
It's a bit big to be a squirrel...
Isn't that a flying squirrel?
Flying squirrel? Wow! This is my first time seeing one!
I wonder if he's the one who dropped the acorn...
They are supposed to be nocturnal,
so it's pretty cool to see one during the daylight.
Geez. Don't drop acrons on my head!
Be careful!
Renge, be careful. There are enemies on this mountain!
You lost to a flying squirrel?
A flying squirrel has teeth and stuff!
And seems dangerous if we get bitten, so it's an enemy!
With that logic, almost all mammals
are your enemies, Nee-chan.
There's a hole over there!
Oh, that's true.
I thought of something good.
Let's make that a house!
Then, let's make that our base and go collect tree nuts!
Aye! Then, let's all go collect tree nuts!
Oh, those are jujubes!
Jujubes? I think I've heard that name before...
It's good! Do you want one?
Y-Yes!
Wow! It tastes like an apple,
even though it looks completely different!
Right?
I found some chocolate vines!
I found some raspberries!
We got a lot!
I should have brought a bag or something.
Do you want me to hold them?
It's fine. I'll leave them at the hole.
It's kinda like a survival game, and it's getting fun!
They said there were some raspberries, so I should...
T...That's the same flying squirrel...
Ah, don't take my jujubes!
Stop it! Don't eat it!
Stop it... Stop it!
Did something happen, Senpai!?
My tree nuts were stolen!
By that thing that's climbing that tree right there...
It had a nest up there?
I wonder if it made that hole on its own.
It's really good at climbing trees.
Ah, there's babies inside the nest!
You're right!
Babies? Where, where?
They're so small and cute!
Weren't flying squirrels your enemy?
Babies are fine!
Maybe it came out during the day
because it was hungry while raising the babies.
Ah, a baby peeked its head out!
There's two babies!
They're pretty lively.
Aren't all of your eyes a little bit too good?
That's right! Let's leave some tree nuts here for them.
I'll leave some too.
Eat a lot and get bigger!
Let's eat the rest in that hole.
Okay!
It's good!
Senpai, do you want some raspberries?
I do!
Here you go.
Thank you.
Ah... The flying squirrel
is there eating tree nuts with its babies!
I finally got to see the babies!
The flying squirrels like tree nuts too, don't they?
It seems like it.
They're like all of us.
Non Non Biyori
Today is up till here.
Le lucciole che saltellano sulla superficie dell'acqua
Sono così belle, come stelle comete!
Mentre noi, spuntando fuori da non si da dove e imitando il canto di una tortora,
Scendiamo lungo questo sentiero sconnesso.
Sotto ad un cielo limpido e stellato,
Prima di accorgercene, ci siamo ritrovati a dormire fianco a fianco!
って
た
Il sole del mattino ci ha sorriso, come a dire " Bentornate! "
おか
え
り
って
Questo è il luogo in cui ci attende il più dolce " Bentornate ! "
おか
え
り
が
待
って
る
場
所
Abbraccerà con dolcezza la tua spensierata vita di ogni giorno!
Questo è il luogo dove la più tiepida primavera ci fa visita
Ascolta, si sentono le voci dei fiori!